[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e4", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Georgia?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d2942596a59cbdfbd390", "question": "Who has won the most Oscars?", "answer": "Katherine Hepburn (4)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65797ae7e414034b5aede", "question": "Facebook co-founder Sean Parker was also the co-founder of which company?", "answer": "Napster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c399", "question": "An \"atomizer\" is a device most often used to distribute what?", "answer": "Perfume", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a666", "question": "What US city is home to the International UFO Museum and Research Center?", "answer": "Roswell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcac", "question": "Because of his butterfly tattoo, what was Henri Cherriere's nickname at Devil's Island prison?", "answer": "Papillon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a4ef20565ad31a57c7c4", "question": "Who was the first lawyer to become US President?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac30", "question": "What ended the Austro-Hungarian monarchy?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049e53cf93664eb10486b3", "question": "The Koson District is a district in the Qashqadaryo Region of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c143", "question": "What wine barrel size contains 10 gallons?", "answer": "Anker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76b", "question": "The curlew is a type of what?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa5b473838c5c8a417f2a", "question": "Automatonophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Ventriloquist dummies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac50", "question": "The earliest evidence of the wheelbarrow was found in which country?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee1", "question": "What bird was used as an alias for Tom Clancy's CIA agent in the Kremlin?", "answer": "The Cardinal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa3f16ce05a3942286ead", "question": "Which national monument does Cary Grant climb in \"North by Northwest\"?", "answer": "Mount Rushmore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a41", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Margaret Mitchell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8b", "question": "What settlers introduced gingerbread houses to Canada in the 1700's?", "answer": "German settlers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b7", "question": "Prior to 2016, which pitcher was the last to win back to back Cy Young Awards in the American League?", "answer": "Pedro Martinez", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338899", "question": "Who were the Three Musketeers?", "answer": "Arthos, Porthos, Aramis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df2", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"commando\"?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b30a", "question": "Who uttered the line \"Senator, you are no Jack Kennedy.\"?", "answer": "Lloyd Bentsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4eb", "question": "How much do you collect when you pass GO in the traditional game of \"Monopoly\"?", "answer": "$200", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6007803bbd51d85e222ab642", "question": "What art critic coined the term \"impressionism\"?", "answer": "Louis Leroy, an art critic for the French newspaper Le Charivari, coined the term to satirize artists evolved in an art show.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b784", "question": "Who invented machine-spun cotton candy?", "answer": "William Morrison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab83", "question": "What year did Sierra Leone gain its independence from the UK?", "answer": "1961", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f73", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Caractacus Potts?", "answer": "Chitty Chitty Bang Bang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a245", "question": "In the TV series \"Seinfeld\", who does Michael Richards play?", "answer": "Kramer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92d", "question": "Where is the Swimming Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Fort Lauderdale, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b862", "question": "What word is both a computer programming language and a nickname for coffee?", "answer": "Java", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339291", "question": "In what fictional town is the TV show \"Veronica Mars\" set?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd143ec223966ae8f88be", "question": "What actor wore prosthetic ears while filming \"Jupiter Ascending\"?", "answer": "Channing Tatum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb6e065ff7d326b622a9b", "question": "Which baseball player was nicknamed \"The Bambino\"?", "answer": "Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70a", "question": "According to Irish superstition, what stands open during the 12 days of Christmas?", "answer": "The gates of heaven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba73", "question": "What Latin phrase is used meaning \u201can attorney representing a client for free\u201d?", "answer": "Pro bono", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d73", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"Life Among the Lowly\"?", "answer": "Uncle Tom's Cabin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940a", "question": "What was the nickname given to the mechanical sharks created for the movie \"Jaws\"?", "answer": "Bruce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb650f5dad637d903c8833", "question": "What African ethnic group is known as \"the people of the veil\" because the men wear veils that conceal all but their eyes?", "answer": "Tuareg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c791", "question": "What continent has the highest native population of cheetahs?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who sings to Homer and the other astronauts in space?", "answer": "James Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab15b4baab681b0929217c", "question": "In what year did the BBC debut the \u201cTop Gear\u201d TV series?", "answer": "1977", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cb70b95f96e155acab35d25", "question": "As of 2018, what NFL quarterback holds the record for most interceptions thrown in their career?", "answer": "Brett Favre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339178", "question": "What picture hangs on Andy Dufresne's cell wall in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A picture of Albert Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20c", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3e4a44f0f6af5b066649", "question": "In mathematics, which prefix refers to 10 to the power of 24?", "answer": "Yotta", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5efa962cccb363a2cbc5227c", "question": "As of 2020, which European country got about 3/4 of its electricity from nuclear power, the most of any country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dfd", "question": "What \"Suddenly Susan\" actor ended up committing suicide?", "answer": "David Strickland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0da", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Republican Speaker of the House in 40 years?", "answer": "Newt Gingrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23f", "question": "What year did Elton John release his fourth studio album \"Madman Across the Water\"?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb01", "question": "What is the chemical element Azote now referred to as?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f04", "question": "What bird was used as an alias for CIA agent Joe Turner in a Robert Redford movie?", "answer": "The Condor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a731", "question": "Miami is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "None, Miami is not a capital city", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c838", "question": "Bauxite ore is mined so it can be processed into what metal?", "answer": "Aluminum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ff", "question": "Mt. Rainier is one of sixteen volcanoes in the world that is classified as what?", "answer": "A Decade Volcano", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdffc7e1cf6db9ac4808cff", "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the Air Capital of the World?", "answer": "Wichita, Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cda", "question": "What British statesman wrote \"A History of the English-Speaking People\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e71", "question": "At the end of \"The Da Vinci Code\", the Holy Grail is revealed to be buried at what popular spot?", "answer": "The Louvre Museum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea77b5ff048f679a45abcd", "question": "What was magnetite called by the early", "answer": "Lodestone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa7", "question": "Who painted \"The 3rd of May\"?", "answer": "Francisco de Goya", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b887", "question": "What does the abbreviation YMCA stand for?", "answer": "Young Men's Christian Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca25", "question": "How many kilograms make up a short ton?", "answer": "907", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecd964ec223966ae8f88e0", "question": "Which of Rocky\u2019s opponents sent Sylvester Stallone to a real hospital?", "answer": "Ivan Drago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3ddbff048f679a45ab54", "question": "What's another name for vitamin B5", "answer": "Pantothenic Acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339910", "question": "The 2004 Kevin Spacey film \"Beyond the Sea\" is a biography of what late singer?", "answer": "Bobby Darin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078a770eee65b76b9f2660", "question": "In the Zimmermann Telegram, Germany proposed an alliance to which nation?", "answer": "Mexico (In 1917, Germany proposed that Mexico could reconquer Texas, Arizona and New Mexico from America during World War.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a29620565ad31a57c7ae", "question": "Who was the first US presidential candidate to speak at a political convention?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad75", "question": "What brothers invented the hot air balloon?", "answer": "Montgolfier", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac35", "question": "Which of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World was alive?", "answer": "The Hanging Gardens of Babylon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c8", "question": "Cr\u00e8me de Menthe, Cr\u00e8me de Cacao and fresh cream are combined to make what drink?", "answer": "Grasshopper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3ad4ff048f679a45ab2f", "question": "What is the shape of DNA known as?", "answer": "Double Helix", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc1", "question": "What onetime NBA Finals MVP was the last owner of the CBA before its 2001 bankruptcy?", "answer": "Isiah Thomas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada4", "question": "In what US state was the outlaw Jesse James born?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b755", "question": "How many days is the Olympic decathlon held over?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b40be662d71a53650fe8", "question": "How many paintings did Claude Monet create for his \"Water Lilies\" series?", "answer": "More than 250", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c957", "question": "Approximately how many miles is an Astronomical Unit?", "answer": "93 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab0fd0baab681b0929216a", "question": "Valentine's Day is also known as the \"Feast of...\" what?", "answer": "Saint Valentine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c245877e98cb97778988", "question": "What is the most populous city in the Middle East?", "answer": "Cairo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b159", "question": "How did Princess Diana die in 1997?", "answer": "Car accident", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c736", "question": "What alloy is comprised of copper and zinc?", "answer": "Brass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59067f4eff9c0647b50a8082", "question": "In October of 2016, just 2 months after its initial release, what product did Samsung stop manufacturing and selling?", "answer": "Galaxy Note 7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66e", "question": "Which have longer snouts - alligators or crocodiles?", "answer": "Crocodiles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35f", "question": "Who was Tommy Lee Jones' upperclassman roommate at Harvard?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96acf23c87fd04dd15e15", "question": "As of 2020, who was the last person to go directly from Vice President to President of the United States?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8b", "question": "Maseru is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Lesotho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b904", "question": "What board game introduced the world to the wonders of pop-o-matic dice?", "answer": "Trouble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339121", "question": "Who wrote the 1895 book \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4d", "question": "What type of device was the first Sony-branded product, released in 1955?", "answer": "Transistor Radio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ed", "question": "What US state has been led by Orval Faubus and Jim Guy Tucker?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7d", "question": "What type of shadow portraits are named for a former French finance minister?", "answer": "Silhouettes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de4", "question": "In the TV show \"Twin Peaks\", what letter was found under Laura Palmer's fingernail?", "answer": "R", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58be2d038faf425cf37add7a", "question": "In Greek mythology, which of the nine Muses is normally depicted sitting down and holding a lyre?", "answer": "Terpsichore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62a", "question": "What is the name of a small object orbiting the sun made of ice, dust and frozen gas?", "answer": "Comet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecda46ec223966ae8f88e7", "question": "What was the first movie by Pixar to receive a rating higher than G in the United States?", "answer": "The Incredibles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c3", "question": "Do identical twins have the same fingerprints?", "answer": "No", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0e", "question": "Moroni is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Comoros", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339849", "question": "Who was the protagonist in Disney's \"The Little Mermaid\"?", "answer": "Ariel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac23", "question": "What countries share land borders with Suriname?", "answer": "French Guiana, Guyana, and Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d07ca1a1c922dd1ac64bc", "question": "Who was the Roman god of sleep?", "answer": "Somnus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbd", "question": "What state saw the start of the American Revolution?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c831", "question": "The \"Wandering\" species of what bird has the longest wingspan in nature?", "answer": "Albatross", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a61a", "question": "Which two states share a border with South Carolina?", "answer": "Georgia and North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b52", "question": "What 1982 comedy film's first sequel was subtitled \"The Next Day\"?", "answer": "Porky's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03e", "question": "What 1953 model of Chevrolet was first commemorated on a US postage stamp in 2005?", "answer": "The Corvette", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c89dca011619dd6d415489", "question": "Whose mom in South Park was sucked into a toilet?", "answer": "Clyde\u2019s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b809", "question": "Who are the Mario Brothers usually trying to save?", "answer": "Princess Peach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5da855641aec824685d88d01", "question": "The \"Curse of the Bambino\" was a popular superstition in which sport?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad9", "question": "What Grand Slam sports event is held at Flushing Meadows, NY?", "answer": "US Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f46a5cb9e8bda6821368", "question": "What year did Charles Perrault publish his version of the folk tale \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "1697", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe0e306fcbed638185eaa1f", "question": "Where is the United Nations (UN) Headquarters located?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad34", "question": "Which company developed the A6M fighter plane known as \"Zero\" during WWII?", "answer": "Mitsubishi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c206", "question": "What year were the Olympic Games hosted in the US for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9f", "question": "In which year was Terry Waite kidnapped in Beirut?", "answer": "1987", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c292", "question": "What color is diamond dust?", "answer": "Black", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f16919f7c52aae91cc07cd", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Moonstone\"?", "answer": "Wilkie Collins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee7", "question": "What is the name of Ron Kovic's bestselling autobiography?", "answer": "Born on the Fourth of July", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ec7234257c9fcac0ce7197b", "question": "As of 2020, who were the last two horses to win the Kentucky Derby and Triple Crown?", "answer": "American Pharoah and Justify", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feddcad6ce05a3942286d9e", "question": "Who hosts the Potterwatch pirate radio show?", "answer": "Lee Jordan hosts Potterwatch to advise listeners on defenses against Lord Voldemort.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943d", "question": "What 2000 movie depicts the war on drugs in Ohio, California and Mexico?", "answer": "Traffic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab03", "question": "In which US state is Mount Vernon?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942e", "question": "What is the name of the school in the 1989 movie \"Dead Poets Society\"?", "answer": "The Welton Academy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c705", "question": "What element's Latin name is \"ferrum\"?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b384", "question": "Mary Read and Anne Bonny had what job in common?", "answer": "Pirates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a695", "question": "What is the official language of Guyana?", "answer": "English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc22b6ce05a3942286f1a", "question": "The powerful mineral vibranium is mined from which fictional country?", "answer": "Wakanda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b27a01dd7bf43be5e79e", "question": "What constellation do some people consider the 13th zodiac sign?", "answer": "Ophiuchus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2f", "question": "What popular figure was assassinated by Sirhan Sirhan?", "answer": "Robert F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25d", "question": "Which famous rapper was born Stanley Kirk Burrel in 1962?", "answer": "MC Hammer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ce", "question": "In 1986, a brittle O-ring seal was determined to be the cause of what?", "answer": "The Challenger disaster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00c", "question": "In the tech field, what does AMD stand for?", "answer": "Advanced Micro Devices", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a988", "question": "What city named its airport after John Foster Dulles?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe52de81bf59ab7d2e3810e", "question": "What is Ronald McDonald called in Japan?", "answer": "Donald McDonald", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e5f0e89d274615ecf514535", "question": "The \"Sherwood Forest Plantation\", home to U.S. President John Tyler, is located in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a725", "question": "Mount Whitney is the highest peak in which mountain range?", "answer": "Sierra Nevada Range", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994c", "question": "What actress replaced Farrah Fawcett on \"Charlie\u2019s Angels\" in 1977?", "answer": "Cheryl Ladd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db78230ab2c8f322317ff2", "question": "Which author wrote about the Cornish seaside boarding school Malory Towers?", "answer": "Enid Blyton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964e", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Mighty Joe Young\"?", "answer": "Gorilla", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86b", "question": "What kind of American desert rat can survive indefinitely without drinking water?", "answer": "The kangaroo rat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bf", "question": "Yellowstone Lake is located in which US state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008dfa7f4f3bc4a292f862d", "question": "Who composed the famous Christmas song \"Jingle Bells\"?", "answer": "American composer James Lord Pierpont composed \"Jingle Bells\" in 1875 for Thanksgiving.  It later became a popular Christmas song.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb0", "question": "Which was the first country to leave the Commonwealth in 1949?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb01b65ff7d326b622a60", "question": "In which continent would you find the Atlas Mountains?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5907201e3745b36be73039ef", "question": "What English singer-songwriter was born on December 25, 1971?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fcc1c5bc97eb73f6a51a273", "question": "What is the longest mountain range on land?", "answer": "The Andes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fa", "question": "What winter Olympic event combines cross-country skiing with rifle shooting?", "answer": "Biathlon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5c795dad637d903c881e", "question": "\"Ital\" is the word used to describe the cuisine of which group of people?", "answer": "Rastafarians", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab1b1ad4fda37788a9a1db3", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Regeneration\" trilogy?", "answer": "Pat Barker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea353bff048f679a45aaff", "question": "Which planet is known as the Evening Star?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d07", "question": "What Marvin Hamlisch musical is about dancers auditioning for a musical?", "answer": "A Chorus Line", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a89d20565ad31a57c7f8", "question": "Who was the first sitting U.S. President to ride a train?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab5", "question": "What brand of cognac calls itself \"Le Cognac de Napolean\"?", "answer": "Courvosier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fd", "question": "The gopher is a member of what order of mammals?", "answer": "Rodents", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339732", "question": "How many hard-boiled eggs does Paul Newman's character eat in \"Cool Hand Luke\"?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967a", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who learned medicine at \"The Hollywood Upstairs Medical School\"?", "answer": "Dr. Nick Riviera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada2", "question": "Robert Leroy Parker was better known as who?", "answer": "Butch Cassidy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25f2b06682715b82711cec", "question": "Margarita Carmen Cansino became famous as who?", "answer": "Rita Hayworth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e9", "question": "In which California city does the 1982 film \"Poltergeist\" take place?", "answer": "Cuesta Verde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf8", "question": "In which movie did Neve Campbell portray a witch?", "answer": "The Craft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94f", "question": "What caused fjords?", "answer": "Glaciers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8a94b01dd7bf43be5e74c", "question": "What is the slogan of Apple Inc.?", "answer": "Think different", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aadd", "question": "Zagreb is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4e", "question": "What popular detective did Robert Downey Jr. portray in a series of movies?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392df", "question": "For what does the \"T\" stand in the name of Star Trek's captain James T. Kirk?", "answer": "Tiberius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c744", "question": "What is the more common name for the bone called the furcula, found in birds?", "answer": "Wishbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f6", "question": "What is the shape of the goat's pupil?", "answer": "Horizontal slit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93d426bd93ce3a4e5f6b2", "question": "What two elements do all silicate minerals contain?", "answer": "Silicon and oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b8", "question": "Which novel is the movie \"Blade Runner\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c8", "question": "The singer Shakira comes from what country?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96087ccba3ffe45786e7", "question": "In Greek mythology, into what did Athena turn Arachne?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b067", "question": "Which Space Shuttle broke apart during re-entry in February, 2003?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da0", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Deep Impact\"?", "answer": "Morgan Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a0", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Taal\"?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339336", "question": "What was the title of the TV series \"M*A*S*H\" theme song?", "answer": "Suicide is Painless", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ae", "question": "Who was the first African-American to win an Academy Award for an acting role?", "answer": "Hattie McDaniel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb4f47e83c707845b211d", "question": "What is the name of the chemical compound that makes peppers hot?", "answer": "Capsaicin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049d91cf93664eb10486ae", "question": "The plane carrying what country\u2019s national rugby team crashed on Friday, October 13, 1972?", "answer": "Uruguay\u2019s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6b834fb6c85e9e634ff4d", "question": "Most common in British towns, what is the name of a street seller of fruits and vegetables?", "answer": "Costermonger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66942a5bfecdd737e0879", "question": "Why do Italians eat lentils on New Year's Eve?", "answer": "To bring good fortune", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a990761d1b4d384d5d695", "question": "What year was the radio show \"Gunsmoke\" adapted for TV?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b58f", "question": "What Cuban products include Montecristo, Cohiba and Romeo y Julieta?", "answer": "Cigars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6ab2f20565ad31a57c825", "question": "Who said, \"Books give a soul to the universe, wings to the mind, flight to the imagination, and life to everything\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d2", "question": "How many land miles are there in a league?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a7dc20565ad31a57c7f0", "question": "What was the first slogan for OREO cookies?", "answer": "Oh! Oh! Oreo!", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be36", "question": "How many players are there in a standard water polo team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397da", "question": "What did Marilyn Monroe claim was the only thing she wore in bed?", "answer": "Chanel No. 5", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a364", "question": "Where is Mount Olympus?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b69912de762b54eb9be9417", "question": "What was the name of the album the band TLC released in 2013?", "answer": "20", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde7", "question": "What sport has thirteen players per team in \"league\" rules but fifteen in \"union\" play?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3d5444f0f6af5b066639", "question": "Who had a hit with the song \"Don't Pay The Ferryman\"?", "answer": "Chris de Burgh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a362", "question": "What US city's skyline boasts the Gateway Arch?", "answer": "St. Louis'", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008e05cf4f3bc4a292f8631", "question": "What artist said, \"Every child is an artist\"?", "answer": "Pablo Picasso (The full quote reads,\u00a0\"Every child is an artist, the problem is staying an artist when you grow up.\")", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899d5360d398dc9cf7a6ac", "question": "What country shares a land border with Papua New Guinea to the west?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf11", "question": "Who was the first professional footballer to be knighted?", "answer": "Sir Stanley Matthews\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69b7220565ad31a57c75f", "question": "What English code breaker created a machine that helped to decrypt Nazi messages?", "answer": "Alan Turing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b88ca1d8c1817608d53f7", "question": "What are the highest and lowest cards in Poker?", "answer": "Ace is highest and 2 is lowest.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339571", "question": "In A Charlie Brown Christmas, what does Lucy want for Christmas?", "answer": "Real Estate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49b", "question": "In what country was the concentration camp \"Treblinka\" located?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85d", "question": "What is the World's 9th largest country by land area?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395bd", "question": "In The Simpsons, when Bart goes to France, what is the name of the mule on the farm where he stays?", "answer": "Maurice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feb34ab7e83c707845b20cc", "question": "Banknote collectors call it \"banana money\", after its artwork. Which country issued it in some of the territories that it oc\u00adcupied during World War II?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bd46fb6c85e9e634ff65", "question": "What element has the periodic table name Sb?", "answer": "Antimony", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c8", "question": "What military cemetery is located across the Potomac River from the Lincoln Memorial?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b1", "question": "What year did the Jallianwahla Bagh massacre occur?", "answer": "1919", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad59", "question": "For what purpose did George Washington Carver originally encourage farmers to grow peanuts?", "answer": "Crop rotation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b6", "question": "Which was the first Space-ready Shuttle to be launched?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4de6206d333868d34d714", "question": "Who is known for running through the streets crying Eureka?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b903", "question": "Who are the 3 original owners of the Planet Hollywood chain of restaurants?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone, Bruce Willis and Arnold Schwarzenegger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949a", "question": "Who played European John Blackthorne in the miniseries \"Shogun\"?", "answer": "Richard Chamberlain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6003958357a0e35c43f83894", "question": "What is the term for reproducing a texture by laying paper over it and rubbing it with a pencil or crayon?", "answer": "Frottage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c818", "question": "In what part of the body would you find chyme?", "answer": "The stomach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ed", "question": "Where is the most dangerous type of thunderstorms?", "answer": "Supercells", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de0", "question": "What former musician played bass on Madonna's \"Like a Prayer\"?", "answer": "Randy Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbae6f40738315b1fb74e24", "question": "What day of the year is considered National Pi Day?", "answer": "March 14th", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7c", "question": "What 1989 hit single contained the following line \"Folks linin' up outside just to get down\"?", "answer": "Love Shack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e147934dd42e4a67cb8d3ed", "question": "Who painted the famous work of art known as \"The Death of Socrates\"?", "answer": "Jacques-Louis David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392dc", "question": "What duo's debut album was titled \"Wednesday Morning, 3 AM\"?", "answer": "Simon & Garfunkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcef", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Bilbo Baggins\"?", "answer": "Leonard Nimoy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015fcddfe83fe1f2a824c46", "question": "Which scientist patented new ballet shoes to protect dancers\u2019 feet?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4c", "question": "What sign are you if you were born on Valentine\u2019s Day?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8f", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was warned that the cow was in the corn?", "answer": "Little Boy Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339283", "question": "Who won part 1 of the final \"Head Of Household\" competition in season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Dan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded2ebea2747c8aff16d43", "question": "What is a device to stem the flow of blood called?", "answer": "A tourniquet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1bc", "question": "Who is often regarded as the designer of the VW Beetle?", "answer": "Ferdinand Porsche", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb0b765ff7d326b622a63", "question": "What sport is Valentino Rossi associated with?", "answer": "Motorcycling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac4d", "question": "What crop failure caused the Irish Famine?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3dbbff048f679a45ab51", "question": "What enzyme is responsible for breaking down starches?", "answer": "Amylase", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339156", "question": "Who said: \"We are more popular than Jesus\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636e3e967692ea851899b2", "question": "What band released their 10th studio album under the name \"Back to Us\"?", "answer": "Rascal Flatts'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe768aaeec85e375820b2a4", "question": "What country once had a banknote that featured a woman riding a shark?", "answer": "Cook Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc1183469bb8041d07a075", "question": "In cooking, what is cutting herbs or vegetables into very fine strips called?", "answer": "Chiffonade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1cda27bd84c0ea43ad42b", "question": "Which country borders Macedonia to the west?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cf", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Red Baron\"?", "answer": "Manfred von Richtofen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e0", "question": "What US city was once called New Amsterdam?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe937c36bd93ce3a4e5f676", "question": "Gamophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Marriage and commitment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f4", "question": "Neptune, the Roman god of water, was known by what name in Greek mythology?", "answer": "Poseidon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba4", "question": "What was the title of Hootie & the Blowfish's 1995 debut album?", "answer": "Cracked Rearview", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e5", "question": "Which actor played the movie character known as \"The One\"?", "answer": "Keanu Reeves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926d", "question": "Which rap star was born Cordozar Calvin Broadus, Jr.?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f44", "question": "\"Pee-Wee's Big Adventure\" is to recover what beloved stolen item?", "answer": "His bike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeff", "question": "What city hosted the Summer Olympics in 1996?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b99a364247bf200fb88e", "question": "Ostraconophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Shellfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957b", "question": "What does Charlie Brown set out to do in the made-for-TV special, A Charlie Brown Christmas?", "answer": "Find the true meaning of Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008fa6cf842fa4c4ba96bf", "question": "In what Australian state would you find the city of Launceston?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad6", "question": "Dustin Hoffman earned his first Oscar nomination for what movie?", "answer": "The Graduate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf4", "question": "Petroselinum crispum is the Latin name of which herb?", "answer": "Parsley", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a837", "question": "The Liffey River runs through what European capital city?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb582f5dad637d903c880f", "question": "What animal is considered to be symbolic of Venice?", "answer": "Lion -- The Lion of St. Mark is a symbol that appears throughout the city.  It honors St. Mark, who is the patron saint of Venice.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fe", "question": "What compound makes up around 60% of the human body weight?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f7e", "question": "Who killed Macbeth?", "answer": "Macduff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339538", "question": "Who played the role of Joey Potter on the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\"?", "answer": "Katie Holmes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b3864fda37788a9a1dc3", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Sparkling Cyanide\"?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8db", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Volta river?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8c", "question": "What occupation traditionally referred to its apprentices as \"devils\"?", "answer": "Printers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8557ec223966ae8f8804", "question": "Which famous golf player was nicknamed \"Golden Bear\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicklaus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015de93fe83fe1f2a824b6e", "question": "What was a boarding device used by ancient Roman ships?", "answer": "Corvus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc40d6ce05a3942286f2b", "question": "Who first recorded the song \"Ain't That A Shame\"?", "answer": "Fats Domino", "category": "entertainment"}]